Ivars Melecis

Email ivars.melecis@gmail.com Address 1 Bradley drive, Grantham

Lincolnshire, NG31 7WN https://melecis.co.uk/

Website https://melecis.c Phone 07754527480

OBJECTIVE

Highly self-motivated individual with great attention to detail and over 9 years of experience in web development industry is looking for new challenge. Gained variety of skills over the years including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Photoshop, XD and WordPress.

Looking forwards to expanding and using current skill set to help reaching KPI's while delivering quality code and making the Web a better

place.

SKILLS

Advanced: HTML, CSS and CSS3, JavaScript, WordPress

Intermediate: MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Adobe Photoshop, jQuery, PHP, GitHub

Entry Level: SCSS, MySQLi, Adobe XD

Worked with: JWT, Winston, Netlify, Heroku, PM2

WORK EXPERIENCE

ROLE

RESPONSIBILITIES INCLUDED:

Web Application Developer

Affinity Agency

February 2022 - Present

Full-stack web developer

Ketchup Marketing

Buckminster

November 2020 - February 2022

Web developer

Ketchup Marketing

Buckminster

November 2019 - November 2020

Website build team leader (Junior Front-end developer)

PrimarySite Limited Newark-on-Trent

August 2017 - November 2019

Website builder (Junior Front-end developer)

PrimarySite Limited Newark-on-Trent January 2015 - August 2017

- Maintaining bespoke in-house WordPress template
- Developing websites using SCSS, HTML, PHP, Gulp, NPM, Adobe XD
- Creating plugins for in-house needs using vanilla JS
- Building e-commerce sites
- Maintaining existing websites
- Performing technical SEO on request (SEMrush, Web CEO)
- Producing websites using SCSS, HTML, JavaScript, Gulp, Node, WordPress and more
- · Creating automation tools for in-house needs
- Creating and maintaining documentation.
- Involved in an in-house automation tool creation that saves company 50 minutesevery day and ensures testing content consistency Involved in code snippet bank development to streamline build processes
- Leading team of 5 to deliver team and department set KPI's
- Created several easy-to-use JavaScript plugins for the team to push our abilities andenhance functionality of our websites Created and maintained documentation for tools used in our day-to-day job
- PSD to working websites using HTML, CSS, and jQuery
- Contributing to teams brainstorming sessions to satisfy customer needs and innovate build processes
- Slicing Photoshop files for usage on illustration-based designs allowing dynamic content
- Best performer exceeding personal KPI's

EDUCATION

Arden University

Manchester October 2020 - Present BSC (Hons) Computing, Information Technology

Programming technician

Centre of distance learning and professional continuing education of Latvia December 2017 - December 2019

Comparison:

UK Framework levels: RQF Level 3/ SCQF Level 6-7/ CQFW Level 3 Comparable UK qualifications: Level 3 NVQ / SVQ Level 3/ SQA Professional Development Award at SCQF Levels 6 (UK NARIC)

Course included:

- Network and database technologies Software Engineering
- WEB technologies and WEB programming Project management
- Programming

Certificate of Competency

Home Learning College (UK) 2013

Course included:

- Internet Fundamentals and Site Planning
- Adobe Dreamweaver's Interface
- Design Principles and Graphic Design
- Creating a Complete Web Standards Site and Productivity features Adding/Styling
 pages features and publishing/managing site Advanced web development HTML5,
 CSS3, PHP and MySQL Bitmaps, frame-by-frame animation, interactivity, and
 publishing

Secondary School

Karla Videnieka Secondary School No 77 Riga, Latvia 2008

Comparison:

UK Framework levels: RQF Level 3/ SCQF Level 6 / CQFW 3 Comparable UK qualifications: GCE Advanced Subsidiary (AS) level /Scottish Higher Additional comparison information: Every subject passed may be considered at least comparable to GCSE grades A* - C (UK NARIC)

CERTIFICATES & COURSES

IELTS language test (Academic) band 7- 2020

Adobe Certified Expert - Dreamweaver CC - 2016

Adobe Certified Associate in Rich Media Using Flash Professional CS6 - 2014

Adobe Certified Associate in Web Communication Using Adobe Dreamweaver CS6 - 2014